# John Guest

Austin, Tx 78741 | 806-441-9488 | johnguestdev@gmail.com | Github | Blog | Portfolio

### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Experienced in developing Full Stack Ruby and JavaScript applications and APIs. I have built my career by learning to operate within and manage teams while consistently delivering strict standards of product and service in fast-paced environments. After a great introduction to object-oriented design and Web/API fundamentals along with Ruby on Rails and Javascript at Flatiron School; React and the MERN stack has been the focus of my personal projects and study since graduation.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript, React, Node.Js, Express, Redux, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Ruby on Rails, API, Git, Github, Heroku platform

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Chicken Tinder - Github | Live Demo | Video Demo

A Tinder-style application to help groups of people decide where to eat. Designed to emulate the menu of a retro diner, a collection of local restaurants is presented to each player and given "thumbs-up" or "thumbs-down".

- Integrates Yelp via API to retrieve search results that are unique to each game
- Creates JS Class Objects and graphic cards for each search result for storage on the client
- Powered by a REST Rails API implementing nested routes utilizing parent-child relationships established with Object Relational Mapping for the purpose of serving serialized JSON data to the client
- Registers player information and results of each game to be used in multiple back-end features

# Trackerbot - Github | Live Demo | Video Demo

An organizational tool in the "Personal Assistant" category developed for the purpose of recording and quickly retrieving locations of household objects that are often misplaced.

- Updates user authentication, login status, and all other user data by implementing actions integrated with Redux-Thunk middleware allowing for asynchronous dispatches to store
- Utilizes a diverse collection of React Components alongside client-side-routing allowing for smooth navigation
- Presents data to the user in a straightforward and simple design inspired by an early command-line interface

## Market Manager - Github | Video Demo

Taking inspiration from software I have used in my time in the grocery industry I designed an application that registers clerks and allows them to create patron profiles to automate the task of recording and updating custom product orders.

- Designed as a logistical interface utilizing various models to manage and organize detailed product orders while maintaining REST standards for nested routes throughout all CRUD actions
- Equipped with third party authentication as well as internal authentication and encryption

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Amazon Logistics**

Austin, TX

Learning Ambassador/ Delivery Service Partner

09/2020 - Present

 Being flexible and able to jump to any position within the team, I was quickly chosen for Learning Ambassador trusted to assist in teaching new associates and helping with any problems or barriers they may have. I soon transitioned to delivery as I appreciate the autonomy and responsibility of maintaining my own workflow.

#### **Whole Foods Market**

Bee Cave, TX

01/2018 - 07/2020

**Full-Service Meat Cutter** 

Excelled in customer satisfaction and oversaw all aspects of the meat department while mastering the craft of
retail meat cutting as a necessary skill needed to adhere to strict quality and health standards. Because of this
and my affinity for customer service, I always held the most customer-oriented positions.

# GoDaddy

Austin, TX

Inside Sales Representative

08/2018 - 11/2018

Generated and utilized leads with Salesforce as a member of a hard-working and high-volume inside-sales team.
 I worked hard for small businesses around the country by giving them access to a network of social media marketing experts.

## **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School
Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript

Austin, TX